statuscake.com 2018-09-14

# Privacy Policy | StatusCake | StatusCake - Website Monitoring

**StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy**

**Summary**

In this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy you can find out:

  1. **About Us**
  2. **The Collection of Data (Including Personal Data) & GDPR**
  3. **What Types of Data Do We Collect & When?**
  4. **Is My Personal Data & Other Information Safe & Secure?**
  5. **How can I Access, Amend, Correct and/or Delete my Personal Data?**
  6. **International Data Transfers**
  7. **Disclosure of Personal Data**
  8. **How Long Do We Keep Your Information**
  9. **Our Cookies Policy**
  10. **Changes to this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy, & Cookies Policy**
  11. **[StatusCake Data Processing Agreement ](https://www.statuscake.com/gdpr-statuscake-data-processing-agreement/)**

**About Us**

TrafficCake Limited, the company which operates StatusCake.com (“ **StatusCake** ”), provides website monitoring services to its customers alerting them when their website has gone done or is experiencing performance issues.  StatusCake also provides other features that advise its customers on, amongst other things, domain expiration, SSL certificate expiration and validity, the presence of malware on their website.

StatusCake was launched in 2012 and is a company incorporated in England and Wales with company number 08250233.  Our registered office is at Third Floor, 12 East Passage, London, England, EC1A 7LP, with our offices being located at 14 Gray’s Inn Road, London, England, WC1X 8HN.

**The Collection of Data (Including Personal Data) & GDPR**

The EU General Data Protection Regulation EU 2016/679 (“ **GDPR** ”) comes into effect on 25th May 2018 and will replace the UK’s Data Protection Act 1998.  The GDPR is intended to not only replace UK data protection legislation, but strengthens and unifies data protection rights for individuals throughout the EU.

The GDPR is intended to give you more control over how companies such as StatusCake collect data from you and how it is used.  In particular GDPR focuses on data collected which is “Personal Data”; such personal data may be your email address, your first and last name, or your IP address.  Where we collect Personal Data this policy tells you where is it collected, the type of data that is collected, the legal basis upon which we process that data, the reason for collecting the data, and the use we make of the data.  Notes are also provided which provide more information on the processing of that particular data source.

If you want to know more about GDPR you can find out more from the UK’s [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/).

**What Types of Data do we Collect & When?**

Below sets out the data that StatusCake gathers from our website visitors and our users.  We detail below when we collect data, the type of data we collect and then what we do with that data and why.

**Point of Collection:** |  

**Signing-up for a StatusCake account**  
  
---|---  
Type of Personal Data Collected: | Upon sign-up we collect: 

  * email address;

  * password; and/or

  * IP address

Basis for Processing:  | The basis upon which we process your personal data is as follows: 

  * when you sign-up for a StatusCake account you are giving us your clear consent that we may process your personal data for those specific purposes set-out in our Terms & Conditions and this Privacy Policy; and/or

  * the processing of your personal data is necessary for the contract you have entered into with us, and enables us to deliver the StatusCake service to you.

Reason for Collection:  | The data collected enables us to create your account and give you a unique and secure way of logging into your account  
Use of Data Collected: | We will use this data to: 

  * enable you to login securely to your account

  * send you emails relating to your account and the StatusCake service including by way of example, on-boarding emails, product updates, and

Notes: | 

  * This data is not shared with any third parties.

  * If you do not wish to receive these emails please [contact us](mailto:support@statuscake.com).

  * StatusCake account passwords are encrypted using Bcrypt; we do not store raw passwords.

  * This data is processed and stored within the UK.

**Point of Collection:** |  

**The Creation of Contact Groups**  
  
---|---  
Type of Personal Data Collected: | When you set-up contact groups we may collect: 

  * email addresses; and/or

  * mobile telephone numbers.

Basis for Processing:  | The basis upon which we process your personal data is as follows: 

  * when you sign-up for a StatusCake account you are giving us your clear consent that we may process your personal data for those specific purposes set-out in our Terms & Conditions and this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy; and/or

  * the processing of your personal data is necessary for the contract you have entered into with us, and enables us to deliver the StatusCake service to you.

Reason for Collection:  | The data collected is used to create your Contact Groups. 

A Contact Group consist of person(s) who will be notified when an alert is triggered within your StatusCake Account; by way of example, when your website goes down, or your domain is due to expire.  
  
Use of Data Collected: | We will use this data to: 

  * send alerts to those person(s) in the manner you have designated.

Notes: | 

  * You should ensure that you have the permission of all person(s) to share their data before you add them to a Contact group.

  * This data is not shared with any third parties

  * If you believe your information has been wrongly added to a Contact Group please contact us.

  * This data is processed and stored within the UK.

**Point of Collection:** |  

**Creation of a Paid Account**  
  
---|---  
Type of Personal Data Collected: | When you upgrade to a paid account may collect some or all of the following (“ **Paid Account Details** ”): 

  * your first and last name;

  * an additional email address for your billing contact;

  * the name of your company;

  * the address of your company; and

  * your company VAT number.

In addition the following information (“ **Payment Details** ”) are collected via our payment gateway:

  * your long debit or credit card number;

  * the card expiry date; and

  * CVC details.

Basis for Processing:  | The basis upon which we process your personal data is as follows: 

  * when you sign-up for a StatusCake account you are giving us your clear consent that we may process your personal data for those specific purposes set-out in our Terms & Conditions and this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy; and/or

  * the processing of your personal data is necessary for the contract you have entered into with us, and enables us to deliver the StatusCake service to you.

Reason for Collection:  | The data collected enables you to subscribe to a StatusCake Paid Account.   
Use of Data Collected: | We will use this data to manage all aspects of your StatusCake Paid Account subscription including by way of example: 

  * creation of a StatusCake subscription;

  * dealing with any queries relating to your subscription and billing;

  * dealing with payment queries; and

  * managing sales leads and renewals.

Notes: | 

  * We make use of a customer-relationship-management tool called SalesFlare to help us manage our sales leads.  The information we share may include your name and/or email address.

  * We do not share your Paid Account Details with any third parties.

  * Your Payment Details are collected, encrypted and securely stored by: (a) when using “PayPal”, by PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. et Cie, S.C.A; or (b) when making a payment by debit or credit cards provided by Visa Europe Ltd, MasterCard Europe S.A., Discover, American Express or other applicable card networks, by Stripe Inc. on our website by our payment gateway provider Stripe.

  * We do not hold any of your Payment Details.

  * Paid Account Details are processed and stored within the UK.

**Point of Collection:** | **Your Navigation & Use of the StatusCake Website & Service** ** **  
---|---  
Type of Data Collected: | When you arrive at the StatusCake website we may use visitor analytics tool to track how you arrived on our website, how you navigate through the website and on to sign-up. 

We may also track the use you make of the StatusCake service, including by way of example, when and how you make use of individual features, when and how you set-up tests and/or alerts.

(collectively “ **Navigational Data** ”)  
  
Basis for Processing:  | The basis upon which we process your Navigational Data is as follows: 

  * when you sign-up for a StatusCake account you are giving us your clear consent that we may process your personal data for those specific purposes set-out in our Terms & Conditions and this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy; and/or

  * the processing of your personal data is necessary for the contract you have entered into with us, and enables us to deliver the StatusCake service to you.

Reason for Collection:  | The Navigational Data collected enables us to understand how you and/or our users as a whole make use of the StatusCake website and service.  
Use of Data Collected: | We may use the Navigational Data collected to: 

  * understand how you and our other users arrive at the StatusCake website and navigate our website;

  * understand how you use the product;

  * use your data individually and/or aggregated to improve the usability of the product; and/or

  * use your data to answer your customer support queries.

Notes: | 

  * When you sign-up for a StatusCake account the Navigational Data which has been collected via Google Analytics and MixPanel may be tied to your StatusCake Account via our customer-relationship-management tool Intercom.  Up until the point of account creation (at which point processing consent is given), we do not tie any of your Navigational Data to your Personal Data.

  * We can opt-out of Google Analytics by clicking [here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  This will not stop you from experiencing the full benefits of the StatusCake website and service.

  * Intercom is used to handle our customer support queries, as well as ensuring that applicable messaging is sent out to you relating to your account.

  * Save as set out above, we do not share your information with any third parties.

**Is My Personal Data & Other Information Safe & Secure?**

We employ a number of steps-and-measures to ensure that all information and Personal Data we collect is protected from unauthorised access, use and/or disclosure.

As well as putting in place technological security measures, we also ensure that our entire team are trained in data security and that each of them have contractual obligations in their contracts of employment not to disclose information to anyone who is not entitled to have it.

**How can I Access, Amend, Correct and/or Delete my Personal Data?**

You have the right at any time to access any Personal Data we hold about you, and where you feel the Personal Information that we hold is not correct, to request that the Personal Information is corrected.  You also have the right to have your Personal Information deleted.

All of the Personal Information, along with other data collected (as noted in the table above) is information that you can access, amend or delete by logging into your StatusCake Account.

If you have any questions about accessing, correcting, amending, or deleting your information then you can [contact us](mailto:support@statuscake.com).

**International Data Transfers**

Any and all Personal Data that we collect from within the EU/ European Economic Area (EEA) and Switzerland is processed and stored within the UK.

In the event that Personal Data is transferred outside of the EU/EEA and/or Switzerland, we ensure that at all times that we provide the same level of privacy protection as is required by the EU-US Privacy Shield framework and/or any other framework determined by the European Commission to provide adequate protection for data transfers from the EU and/or Switzerland to the US.

**Disclosure of Personal Data**

We will not disclose your Personal Data to any third party unless as otherwise explicitly set out in this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy.  We may however at times be required by law, a competent regulatory authority, by a court, to disclose your Personal Information.   Where this occurs we will where it is practical for us to do so and/or to the extent that we are not otherwise restricted from doing so, notify you before disclosing your Personal Data.

**How Long Do We Keep Your Information**

The length of time we keep your Personal Data and other information will depend on both the nature of the information we have gathered and the use we make of that information.

Unless we are required by law to keep your Personal Data and other information for a certain amount of time, we will not ordinarily keep your information longer than is necessary, given the purpose for what that information for collected by us.

**Our Cookies Policy**

**What is a Cookie?**

A cookie is a small text file, which is unique to you and allows the TrafficCake Websites to recognise your computer or any such other device which you may use from time-to-time for browsing the Internet (collectively “ **Your Computer** ”).

We may use cookies and other “tags” (sometimes referred to as “ **web-beacons** ” or “ **pixel-tags** ”) (collectively “ **Cookie(s)** ”) to provide you with a more personalised service on the TrafficCake Websites or to aid or track your navigation around our website.

If you do choose not to accept any of our Cookies some of the functionality or personalised version of the TrafficCake Websites may not be available to you.

**When Do We Use Cookies?**

When you register to receive information on the TrafficCake Websites and/or register to use the TrafficCake Services we may allocate a Cookie to Your Computer (“ **Registration Cookie** ”).

A Registration Cookie may hold any information collection during your registration or sign-up and allows us to recognise you and provide you with the information or services that you require. If your browser is not set to accept Cookies you may not be able to register for and/or sign-up for the TrafficCake Services.

In addition to Registration Cookies we may from time-to-time use other types of Cookie to gather information. Such Cookies may include, but not be limited to “session-based” Cookies which are allotted to Your Computer for the duration of your visit to the TrafficCake Websites, but will be deleted when you close down your Internet browser.

All use of Cookie gathered information is made in accordance with our StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy.

**Changes to this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy, & Cookies Policy**

This StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy, along with our Cookies Policy, may be modified from time-to-time.  We recommend that you regularly review this page to ensure that you are aware of any changes made to it.

You will be bound by any changes to this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy from the moment you make any use of the StatusCake service after amendments have been made.

In the event that we make any material changes to this StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy we will take reasonable efforts to notify you of those changes, by way of example only, whether through in-app notification or by email.

**StatusCake GDPR Compliance Statement & Privacy Policy – Last Updated 24 April 2018**

**StatusCake Data Processing Agreement**

A copy of the StatusCake Data Processing Agreement that you enter into with us when signing up for a StatusCake account can be found [here](https://www.statuscake.com/gdpr-statuscake-data-processing-agreement/).
